Guide to the Tommy Turner Film Collection MSS.099
Fales Library and Special Collections
Tommy Turner Film Collection
circa 1980-1989
Fales Library and Special Collections
Turner, Tommy, 1959-
MSS.099
2 Linear Feet
The Tommy Turner Film Collection encompass the filmmaker's original film elements for "Where Evil Dwells" (1985, created in collaboration with Daid Wojnarowicz), as well as prints of "Simonland "(1984, created in collaboration with Richard Kern) and "Rat Trap" (1986, created in collaboration with Tessa Hughes-Freeland).
Scope and Contents
The Tommy Turner Film Collection consists of 28 Super8mm reels.
Biographical Note
The Tommy Turner Film Collection encompass the filmmaker's original film elements for "Where Evil Dwells" (1985, created in collaboration with Daid Wojnarowicz), as well as prints of "Simonland "(1984, created in collaboration with Richard Kern) and "Rat Trap" (1986, created in collaboration with Tessa Hughes-Freeland).
Turner was in possession of most of the materials created for "Where Evil Dwells." Unfortunately, much of the footage was lost in a fire at Turner's apartment before the film was completed. What remains is included in this collection. Among the reels is an "epic trailer" version of the film that Turner and Wojnarowicz put together. Other reels include raw footage for the project.
Provenance
Films donated by Tommy Turner to Fales Library in October 2014, after being on deposit since 1999.
Related Materials
David Wojnarowicz Papers (MSS.092)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Experimental films; New York (N.Y.).
- Series I: Motion Picture Film and Video Recordings, 1985 - 1986
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
  - Where Evil Dwells - Extended Trailer, 1985; 099.0001 (Film 099.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Gauge: Super 8mm
    Black and White, Sound
    Length: 600 feet
    Duration: 33 minutes
    This title is available in the David Wojnarowicz Papers, MSS 092.
    Access DVD available. Please request ID #092.0500.
    16mm release print available. Please request 092.0139.
  - Where Evil Dwells Outtakes Roll 2, [1985] (Film 099.0003)
    Length: 600ft
    Duration: 33:00
  - 'Ass Kick' Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0004)
  - Roll 'CP' (Rot, Mall, Sacraments, Hell, Bridge, Dummy), [1985] (Film 099.0005)
  - Dust Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0006)
  - A-PT.2 'Bits' (Hell Stuff-Caven Pt.), [1985] (Film 099.0007)
  - A-PT. 2, [1985] (Film 099.0008)
  - Party Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0009)
  - Dog Head Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0010)
  - Maggot Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0011)
  - Hell Reel, [1985] (Film 099.0012)
  - Graveyard Ripoff, [1985] (Film 099.0013)
  - Donuts, [1985] (Film 099.0014)
  - Woji At Horror House, [1985] (Film 099.0015)
  - Cigarette Trick, [1985] (Film 099.0016)
  - Snow Fun At The Top, [1985] (Film 099.0017)
  - Buses, [1985] (Film 099.0018)
  - Graveyard Approach, [1985] (Film 099.0019)
  - Roll M.C., [1985] (Film 099.0020)
  - Stacy And Baby, [1985] (Film 099.0021)
  - Stacy And Baby 2, [1985] (Film 099.0022)
  - Stacy And Baby 3, [1985] (Film 099.0023)
  - Stacy And Baby 4, [1985] (Film 099.0024)
  - Stacy And Baby 5, [1985] (Film 099.0025)
  - Bonfire, [1985] (Film 099.0026)
  - Bookstore Bits, [1985] (Film 099.0027)
  - Roll HL, [1985] (Film 099.0028)
  - Rat Trap, 1986; 099.0029 (Box Digitized Access Files, File 099.0029, Film 099.0029, Film Preservation Color Internegative 099.0029_0, Film Preservation Negative Optical Soundtrack 099.0029_1, Film Preservation Color Release Print 099.0029_2, Film Preservation Answer Print 099.0029_3)
    Super 8mm, 440 ft, 11 min, 24 fps, Black and White, Sound
    This film was preserved in 2017. A 16mm release print and an HD digital master are available for exhibition. Please contact an NYU Special Collections archivist for access.
  - Simonland, 1984; 099.0030 (Box Digitized Access Files, File 099.0030, Film 099.0030, Film Preservation Color Release Print 099.0030_1, Film Preservation Color Release Print 099.0030_2, Film Preservation Negative Optical Soundtrack 099.0030_3, Film Preservation Color Internegative 099.0030_4)
    Super 8mm film, 440ft, 11 min, 24 fps, Color, Sound
    This film was preserved in 2017. A 16mm release print and an HD digital master are available for exhibition. Contact an NYU Special Collections Archivist for access.